Excuse me guys, question for
you. Are you guys business owners?
Oh, you're the Instagram guy.
Yes, sir. Could I ask you a couple questions?
Just ask away, we'll give you an answer.
How much did you guys sell your company for?
Well, I think the first
company sold for around $25 million,
and then the second company sold for around $200 million,
and we sold to a company that's now $10 billion.
Lately, there's been kind of a
trend where people are bashing billionaires.
I don't get it.
What industry did you guys pursue a career
in? What did you do for a living?
Intellectual property and technology law.
What is your net worth?
$110 million.
Are you self-made?
Yeah, 100% self-made. Probably about
as self-made as you get.
And how can somebody become
a nine-figure entrepreneur in today's world?
If you meet billionaires, like I've
been a part of Harvard, MIT,
CEO programs, every billionaire I met has said this.
We've all heard that some of
the biggest business deals in the world
have been closed on golf courses.
So today, I'm going to be going
around some of the wealthiest golf courses
in all of Texas to
ask multi-millionaires and business moguls
what they did for a living to become millionaires
and how you can start
your path to becoming financially free
in 2020.
So with that being said, let's
get this video on the way.
Excuse me, guys.
Question for you guys.
I started a channel at
the University of Texas at Austin.
No way.
I grew a tour.
These two guys went to
the University of Texas at Austin.
That's amazing.
You started a channel.
I did.
I grew it to over 3
million followers in about two years.
And I go all over the country just asking people
a few quick questions on some of their advice
to the younger generation.
You probably got to the wrong group.
No.
I've done interviews with Mark Cuban, the president of Nike,
some really cool people.
I'd love to just know if
I could ask one of you guys
or just somebody just a couple quick questions.
Just ask away.
We'll give you an answer.
I guess, what industry did
you guys pursue a career in?
What did you do for a living?
We were in the oil and gas business.
And he was in the banking business.
And he's in real estate?
Yeah.
Oil and gas business is very competitive.
What's the number one thing that you guys did
to stand out in this business?
What do you look for in
young people that tells you that,
hey, you're going to be successful?
It's harder the younger you are.
But as you start moving up
and have a little bit of say-so,
best advice I can say
is get equity in your company.
Either stock options, phantom stock,
own a piece of whatever you're working for.
Because you can live off of a salary,
but equity builds wealth.
So ownership is key.
Ownership.
You got to have anything.
I mean, ownership is number one.
What was the best financial advice
that you received from a mentor throughout your career?
If there's a lesson about money that somebody taught you
that always stuck with you,
what's that advice you pass on?
You don't borrow short-term money on a long-term venture.
Whatever financing, if you have a long-term investment,
you better have long-term financing.
Otherwise, if you have short-term financing
on a long-term venture,
then it could go away from you quickly
and you could get it taken away from you.
What were you doing in oil and gas?
Like, what exactly were you doing in oil and gas?
Ran the company.
President.
Among yourself and the most highly successful people
that you study and know,
what is that one trait
that they all have in common?
Integrity.
Integrity?
How important is it to keep your word in business?
Very.
Yeah.
Well, that's it.
There's a lot of guys out
there you want to hit up.
Yes, sir.
I appreciate you guys.
Thank you.
So I know we're going around golf courses today,
but I have a very special surprise for you guys.
We're about to go interview a nine-figure entrepreneur
at his mansion out here in Austin, Texas.
His net worth is over $100 million.
And I'm going to ask him his best advice
for somebody trying to become
a nine-figure entrepreneur in today's world
and how you can start
your path to becoming a millionaire.
So with that being said,
let's go see what he has to say.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career
in?
Medical device.
So I went into medical device sales 14 years ago
and then started distributorship
and then ended up starting my own company.
What is your net worth?
$110 million.
Are you self-made?
Yeah, 100% self-made.
Probably about as self-made as you get.
And how can somebody become a nine-figure entrepreneur
in today's world?
When I was a stockbroker,
we were taught to train investors to be diversified.
If you meet billionaires,
I have been a part of Harvard, MIT CEO programs.
Every billionaire I met has said the exact opposite.
They say if you believe in something,
you find something that's good,
you invest in yourself,
you put all of your money into it,
you put all your money
into that and you grow it.
And that's what I did with my company.
I self-funded it, put all my money in that company.
I have control over that
and it grew bigger and bigger.
And how much is that company worth now?
The main one's over 100 million,
probably 130 million is the net value of it.
So how did you scale this business
from eight to nine figures?
There's two books.
One's called E-Myth.
The other book's called Scaling Up.
Both of them talk about the turnkey method.
You prove the model and then you duplicate it.
Copy, paste, copy, paste, copy, paste.
So we did this in one state in California
in the very beginning.
And now we're in 43 states.
We prove the model.
We bring in the sales rep.
We take care of hospitals, surgery centers.
And we just do that over and over again.
What was the lowest point in your career
as an entrepreneur?
About three years ago when we grew too fast.
There's a quote in business.
And it basically says that more companies
die from indigestion than starvation.
So it means the company
didn't dry up because of sales.
We actually grew so fast in sales
that we ran out of money
because we couldn't make enough product quick enough.
And it almost killed us.
And it was a valuable
lesson that you want to grow,
but you want to grow sustainably as an entrepreneur,
not grow too fast.
You can actually grow a company too quickly.
What is your advice to someone trying to find
that winning product in whatever industry that they're in?
You got to go out there
and try a bunch of stuff.
You know, I was a stockbroker
for two years out of college
and I was horrible.
I was not very good at what I did.
And I went into medical device
and after years and years of talking to doctors
and surgery centers,
I found that one thing that,
hey, nobody's attacking this.
And then how do we make it better?
And then, you know, over three, four, five, six years
of making that product better month by month by month,
that's how we evolved.
And then you reach that tipping point
where you're not making sales calls anymore.
People want your device because they hear about it.
People.
This changes, this saves lives.
It's a great medical product.
We want it.
And that's when it becomes fun.
It's you're not selling anymore.
They want your stuff.
That was phenomenal.
Let's go, bro.
As Jeremy said,
he spent years going back and forth with doctors
and his prospective clients
to really figure out what their problems were.
And as soon as he was able to come up
with the solutions to these,
he was able to build winning products
that sold for millions of dollars
and ultimately build a nine figure business.
And if you own a business
that relies heavily on communication
with your clients to close deals,
whether that's through phone calls or text messaging,
did you know that you can automate
up to 90% of these
interactions and eliminate 30% of your costs?
This is all possible.
Thanks to the sponsor of today's video.
Next Diva.
Next Diva is an AI driven platform
that gives you seamless,
personalized customer interactions
across all channels.
Next Diva allows you to create new phone numbers
and gives you unlimited texting and calling
as well as an auto attendant
that you can run from your personal phone
or your computer.
You also get an AI powered dashboard
that will show you all of your conversations
in just one platform.
This includes an AI voice
and an AI chat bot
that can interact and communicate
directly with clients for you.
You get all of this inside
of one.
One app.
No longer will your team have to switch
between 18 different apps
just to get the job done.
This is your year
to level up your business,
lower your costs
and take full advantage of AI.
So go to trynextdiva.com
slash hard knocks
or click the link down
in the description below
to get 50% off of your plan.
You won't want to miss out on it.
With that being said,
let's go get this next interview.
All right, you guys,
we're at our next golf course right now.
It looks like they got some boogers out.
So we're to go up
and see if we can
talk to some of these people
and get some game for you guys.
Come on.
Excuse me, guys.
Question for you.
I started a channel out here in Austin, Texas
with over 3 million followers.
I go all over the country
just asking people a few questions
on some of their best advice
to the younger generation
and kids coming out of school.
I wanted to know
if I could ask you a couple quick questions
for the channel.
Sure.
Is that cool?
I can't speak for David.
Yeah, you can ask him.
I got you.
I appreciate you.
My kids don't listen to me.
3 million people won't even...
Oh, I promise you they will.
I value your perspective if they don't.
How much did you guys sell your company for?
Well, I think the first company
sold for around 25 million
and then the second company
sold for around 200 million
and we sold to a company
that's now 10 billion dollars.
How old are you now?
I'm 70.
Today is my birthday, actually.
You turned 70 today?
Yeah, yeah.
If you were to go back in time
and have a conversation
with your 20-year-old self
when you were starting from zero,
what's the best piece of advice
you'd tell your younger self?
I would say don't waste time.
The great thing about America
is that there's opportunity for everyone.
Everybody's coming here, okay?
They want to come here.
People coming from El Salvador
with a kid on their back
and that sort of thing,
these are strong people, right?
They mow down the competition
because they're not entitled.
They work incredibly hard.
They see the opportunity, right?
You know, the thing today
that really gets me is,
you know, people are bashing America.
It's like, wow,
you should watch more videos or something
or go some places
because, you know,
this is really great.
You know, the interesting thing
is that 87% of people in America
believe in free enterprise, right?
And so Democrat, Republican, Independent,
87% of people agree
they believe in free enterprise, right?
And there's that opportunity here.
And lately, there's been a trend,
this is not really entitlement,
but lately there's been kind of a trend
where people are bashing billionaires.
I don't get it, okay?
And I like it.
I'm linking it to, you know,
750 billionaires in America, right?
There's 350 million people.
And in a society that believes in free enterprise,
that's going to happen.
So here we're on the golf range,
I say like Tiger Woods, right?
For example, he's at his peak
and people are saying,
hey, give him a softer ball, right?
He's too successful, okay?
I don't get this at all.
And I don't know where it's coming from.
And that to you,
the modern world is social media,
the bots, the people behind
driving these narratives, right?
You don't know who they are.
And so my message to younger people
is to study, okay?
Whatever it is,
before you formulate opinion,
really get some facts
and understand the surroundings.
Don't just watch a TikTok video
and say you believe in it.
Thank you so much for your time.
I appreciate you, sir.
Have a great day, sir.
All right, you guys.
My guy was part of a company
that sold for over $200 million.
And he just laid out the blueprint
for you guys, man.
I can't say enough great things
about that interview, man.
The golf course moguls are out
and they're going crazy.
Let's go get this next interview.
Excuse me, guys.
Question for you.
Are you guys business owners?
Oh, you're the Instagram guy.
Yes, sir.
So cool.
Absolutely, man.
He came to the right place.
Could I ask you a couple questions?
You can, but I'm not in your league, though.
No, it's all good, man.
I guess, like, what industry
did you pursue a career in?
Intellectual property and technology law.
Really?
Yeah.
So are you a lawyer or?
Yeah, I'm still a lawyer.
I just retired about a year ago.
What was the most amount of money
that you made in a single year?
I did have one good year.
I made about a million dollars.
A million dollars?
Yeah.
What was the best financial advice
that you received throughout your career?
I invest in the stock market.
You know, it was probably,
I think, Warren Buffett
that gave the advice
which I think is very true.
You know, be greedy
when others are scared
and be scared
when other people are greedy.
So, you know,
when you see the markets
getting near a top,
you have to consider
getting out of it a little bit.
When you see it's getting really low,
that's the time to invest, right?
The theory, right,
is to buy low, sell high.
But it's easy to say
and it's so hard to do
because the psychology
is exactly the opposite, right?
The psychology is
you see everything going up, up, up,
people making money,
that's when you want to buy.
And then you see things crashing,
people panic,
and they want to sell, right?
So the psychology
is to actually do the opposite, right?
To buy high and sell low.
But you want to buy low, sell high.
And that means doing the opposite
of what other people are doing
at various times in the market.
How old are you now?
Tomorrow will be my 59th birthday.
59th birthday.
Well, happy early birthday to you.
Thank you, I appreciate it.
What's the best piece of advice
that you would give to your younger self?
If you're going through hell,
just keep on going
because eventually you'll get out.
You know, I've always had a belief in God,
but it was really only
in the last 10 years
that I started feeling like
at the important points in my life,
God has come through for me.
And there've been too many things
that have happened by coincidence
that make me discount the fact
that by having that faith
and that belief,
eventually, like we talked about earlier,
you know, you're going to come out
at the low times
and things are going to be better
than they were even before.
So what do you think is more important?
Book smarts or street smarts?
Street smarts.
Why?
I mean, how many times do you solve
a differential equation
in the real world, right?
You don't.
I mean, you don't.
You got amazing advice, sir.
Thank you so much for taking the time to...
Keep up the great work.
I appreciate you.
Hard Knocks family,
the golf courses were insane today.
We got some of the craziest content
we've ever shot in this video,
so we want you to like and subscribe
for amazing content we have coming very soon
because we're on a mission
to bring you guys the best advice
from some of the most successful people
in the entire world.
And if you haven't seen it yet,
we recently launched the Hard Knocks newsletter
where we're going to be sending out
weekly updates, insights, and lessons
from the world's top entrepreneurs
and business owners.
So click the link in the description below
to subscribe
because you do not want to miss out on this.
But with that being said,
that's a wrap on today's video.
So click here to watch our full video
going all over Miami
asking multi-millionaires
how they became wealthy
and how you can start your path
to becoming financially
free in 2024.
We'll see you guys in the next video.